George A. Baxter Papers WLU.Coll.0003
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
George A. Baxter Papers
Inclusive 1797-1893
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Baxter, Louisa
Foote, William Henry
Grigsby, Hugh Blair
Plumer, William S. (William Swan)
Graham, Samuel L. (Samuel Lyle)
Baxter, George Addison
Coulling, Martha
WLU.Coll.0003
4 Linear Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Baxter Family Correspondence and papers, 1797-1918 were a gift of Mary Coulling and Martha Coulling.
Scope and Contents
Includes letters from G.A. Baxter to his wife, Anne Fleming Baxter, and 104 letters from miscellaneous correspondents dealing with the Union Theological Seminary and Presbyterian affairs; reminiscences of Louise Baxter, and letters to her; citations, certificates, and business receipts.Includes three generations of Baxter family correspondence. Also includes a biography of George A. Baxter, sermons written by George A. Baxter, assorted Presbyterian newspaper articles, and three photographsFamily papers reflect the social life of 19th century Virginia, including a personal recipe book, as well as a folder on the genealogy of the Fleming family and a letter to Louisa Baxter from a missionary's wife in China.
Other correspondents include Alexander Tedford Barclay, Louisa Baxter, William Brown, William Henry Foote, Edward Graham, Samuel L. Graham, Hugh Blair Grigsby, and William Swann Plumer.
Missionaries; Recipes; Correspondence; Genealogy; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Receipts (Acknowledgments); Personal Narratives; China; Presbyterian Church; Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.; Baxter, Anne Christian Fleming; Brown, William G.; Washington College (Lexington, Va.); Baxter family; Fleming family; Robinson, John; Union Theological Seminary in Virginia; Coulling, Martha
- Control Folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Anne Fleming (Mrs. George) Baxter- Correspondence, 1805 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Anne F. (Mrs. George) Baxter- Correspondence, 1831-1845 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- George Addison Baxter- Correspondence, 1799-1809 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- George A. Baxter- Correspondence, 1816-1823 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- George A. Baxter- Correspondence, 1826-1830 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- George A. Baxter- Correspondence, 1831-1832 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- George A. Baxter- Correspondence, 1833-1834 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- George A. Baxter- Correspondence, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- George A. Baxter- Correspondence, 1836-1837 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- George A. Baxter- Correspondence, 1838-1839 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- George A. Baxter- Correspondence, 1840-1841 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- George A. Baxter- Correspondence, No Dates (Box 1, Folder 13)
- George A. Baxter- Citations and Certificates, 1797-1867 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- George A. Baxter- Lectures, No Dates (Box 1, Folder 15)
- George A. Baxter- Lectures cont., No Dates (Box 1, Folder 16)
- George A. Baxter- Misc. Church Papers and Resolutions, No Dates (Box 2, Folder 17)
- George A. Baxter- Misc. Papers, No Dates (Box 2, Folder 18)
- George A. Baxter- Misc. Recipts, 1795-1844 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- George A. Baxter- Estate Prince Edward Country Inventory, No Dates (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Louisa Baxter- Correspondence, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Louisa Baxter- Correspondence, 1856-1884 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Louisa Baxter- Reminiscences of George A. Baxter, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Louisa Baxter- Correspondence, 1886-1893 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Louisa Baxter- Reminiscences of George A. Baxter, No Date (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Louisa Baxter- Reminiscences and Resignation of Dr. Baxter from W&L, No Date (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Louisa Baxter- Reminiscences of George A. Baxter, No Date (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Louisa Baxter- Correspondence, 1845-1853 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Louisa Baxter- Misc. Items and Receipts, 1853-1867 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Louisa Baxter- Receipts and Undated Business Papers, 1890-1891 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Baxter Family- Correspondence, 1826-1840 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Baxter Family- Land Vouchers, 1856-1859 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Baxter Family- Tax Vouchers, 1849-1879 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Presbyterian Church USA- General Assembly USA, 1838 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Presbyterian Church USA- Resolution of General Assembly, 1835 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Union Theological Seminary- Subscriptions and Scholarships, 1833, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- George A. Baxter- Obituaries Misc., No Dates (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Baxter Family- Empty Envelopes and Fragments, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Control (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Samuel Ramsey- Correspondence, 1797-1812 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Eliza Ramsey- Correspondence, 1798-1833 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- James M. Coulling- Correspondence, 1811-1815 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Anne Fleming- Correspondence, 1799-1809 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- George A. Baxter- Correspondence, 1798-1840 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- George A. Baxter and Family- Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, and Sermons, 1814-1845 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Ann Christian Kent- Correspondence, 1831-1852 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Joseph F. Baxter- Correspondence, 1837-1864 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Louisa Baxter- Correspondence, 1870-1897 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Letters to Louisa P. Baxter- Correspondence, 1838-1895(?) (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Letters to Elizabeth Baxter- Correspondence, 1836-1857; Letter dated June 9, 1851, from Anne S. Rice of Rice Hill, Virginia to Elizabeth Baxter concerning a former Rice family slave, Hannah, and her condition in Liberia. Hannah was emancipated by the Rice family and sent to Liberia. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  American Colonization Society; Rice, Anne S. (Anne Smith Morton), 1785-1867
- Sidney S. Baxter- Correspondence, 1831-1859 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Sidney S. Baxter cont.- Correspondence, 1860-1879 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Anna Nickolls (Mrs. Sidney) Baxter- Correspondence, 1824-1867 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- William (Willie) Fleming Baxter- Correspondence, 1856-1867 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- George (the younger) Baxter- Correspondence, 1837-1862 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Thornton Baxter- Correspondence, 1853-1864 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Miscellaneous letters, 1822-1918 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Assorted Newspaper Articles, 1866-1884 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Assorted Newspaper Articles, 1867-1891 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Assorted Newspaper Articles, 1881-1902 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings I (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings II (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Control Folder (Box 5, Folder 1)
- George A. Baxter- Correspondence and Printed Documents, 1819-1847 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- George A. Baxter- Sermon and Correspondence, 1832-1866 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- George C. Baxter- Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Joseph Fleming Baxter- Sermons and Correspondence, 1845-1880, No Date Sermons (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Louisa Baxter- Correspondence, 1837-1878 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Louisa Baxter- Correspondence and Will, 1885- 1893 and a No Date (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Martha (Mattie) Nickolls Baxter- Correspondence, 1858-1898 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Mary Selina Baxter- Correspondence, 1860-1871 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Nancy Baxter- Recipe Book, No Date (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Baxter Sisters- Correspondence, 1836-1887, No Date letter; Letter dated November 21, 1843 from Anne S. Rice to Nancy M. Baxter concerning the health of enslaved person Hannah, formerly owned by the Baxter Family and then by the Rice family. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Rice, Anne S. (Anne Smith Morton), 1785-1867; Baxter, Nancy M.
- Sidney Smith Baxter- Correspondence and Book, 1856-1879 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Thorton Baxter- Correspondence, 1860-1864 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- William (Willie) Fleming Baxter- Correspondence, 1860-1871 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Fleming Genealogy (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Nickolls Papers, 1820-1862 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- See Family Correspondences and Obituary, 1861-1918; See, Charles S. M. (Charles Sydney Mathews), 1826-1903 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Scope and Contents
  Folder includes letters written by Charles S. M. See to his aunt Louisa Baxter during the American Civil War. Includes description of early war situation in Tucker (W. Va.) and Augusta County, Virginia. One letter details the death of his brother George Baxter See in a Confederate hospital in 1864. Another details Charles' capture and confinement in both the old Capital Prison in Washington D.C. and Johnson's Island Prison in Ohio. This letter also mentions President Abraham Lincoln's assassination and the surprisingly cordial relations of Unionists and Secessionists in the immediate post war period in Tucker County, West Virginia.
  See, George Baxter, 1829-1864; Lincoln, Abraham; See, Jacob Warwick, 1798-1862; See, Mary Anne Baxter, 1804-1874; See Family
- A Solemn Summons, 1775 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Letter from George Addison Baxter to Anne Fleming on the death of William Graham, 1799-06-17 (Box 5, Folder 18)